Damn it... I wanted to stop
the raid on the mansion,
but I think I just made it inevitable.
Hah! Well, hearin' all that
sure made me feel good.
If that hadn't been a negotiation
to resolve things peacefully,
I might have agreed with you.
I have to get to the mansion
as fast as possible!
Yet here I am...
To say we're short-handed right
now is an understatement.
Well, I'll go with ya, then.
Huh?
What?
Are you sure you understand?
Going to the mansion means
leaving the Sanctuary.
Wouldn't the barrier stop you?
Barrier?
That ain't a problem.
Huh?!
Like my sister, I have a
mixed-blood dad and a human mom.
My mixed blood's too thin for it to stop me.
But I heard you and Frederica
had different fathers!
Huh? Well, y'know...
My mom had shit for luck and
shit for taste in men.
You figure it out!
You should've told me that sooner!
I'm already the strongest
there is, but with these,
I'll be even stronger!
Give us a good show of
just how strong you are!
You can count on it.
No one can run from Reinhard, as they say.
He's still alive, and he
already has his own idiom?
Seriously?
Everything's ready here, too.
Now we just have to hope Elsa
and her partner aren't early.
I'm counting on you guys and on our enemy!
That's the art of war, Natsuki Subaru style!
My Reverse Fuurinkazan!
Th-That's so cool!
Thanks for all the help, you two morons!
Can't you just thank people
normally, you one moron?!
So anyway, Ram...
The rest is up to you.
Fine. Do as you like.
I'm going to do as I like from this point on.
Ram...
Don't do anything crazy.
Is that for you to say, Barusu?
Don't make me laugh.
Okay, people!
Sorry this has all been so irregular, but...
Subaru-sama,
you need not worry about us.
Our internal officer has
already told us everything.
Go on, get moving!
But you should probably wipe
your nose off when it bleeds.
You don't want Petra to be disappointed!
Thanks, you guys!
But...
Subaru-sama, just give
up and let us help you!
Um, who's your internal offic—
Off we go!
So the three idiots hitched the carriage
to their very clever ground dragon
and set off for the mansion.
All right, I understand.
Honestly, what am I going to do with him?
Is that all?
I guess I am still a little angry.
Did Subaru really mean it
when he said he loved me?
Barusu cares about you more than anyone else.
Right. Thank you.
Emilia-sama, does your return mean that...
The trial?
Yes. I was able to confront my past,
but it seems there are two more trials to go.
So I'll have to go into
the graveyard again later.
You truly have grown stronger.
Emilia-sama, I am truly sorry.
What brought this on?
This is the first time I've ever
lowered my head and meant it.
Before now, I didn't believe that
you would get back on your feet.
But here you are now,
standing in front of me,
with your chest high and
your eyes facing forward.
You only lose a few points for the
tear marks remaining on your cheeks.
Huh? Oh, darn it!
So did you help Subaru and Otto-kun
because you thought I was just a crybaby?
Don't be silly. It was you I helped,
and you who determined that
helping would be worth my while.
It... was? But why?
What made you decide to help me?
When asking for something,
one must show one's sincerity.
I beg of you, Emilia-sama.
Please save my master, Roswaal-sama.
Roswaal?
He has become possessed by delusions.
Delusions that have bound his soul
like a curse for a long, long time.
I might not have have minded that.
Even if he wouldn't look at me,
even if he only thought of me as a tool...
Ram...
But his delusions have already strayed
from the path toward a clean conclusion.
His wish has lost its direction,
and he clings to words written
purely for aesthetics.
Please break through that.
What should I do?
Assume the royal throne.
Once you assume the throne of Lugunica,
Roswaal-sama's wish will be fulfilled.
Even if he's walked astray
from his path for so long,
the day his wish comes to fruition will come.
Please tell Roswaal-sama that.
Give him a reason to live through
both present and the future.
Please, Emilia-sama.
Please save him.
I don't quite understand what my becoming
the ruler has to do with saving Roswaal.
I don't think I can truly understand
your wishes just yet, either.
But...
This is the first time you've
ever asked anything of me.
All right, Ram.
You believed in me, and I want to repay that.
I'm sure that's something I
have to start on by myself now.
Would you mind...
if I offered my congratulations to you, too?
That's close enough.
Well, well...
What a fine welcome this is, Emilia-sama.
Despite how I may appear,
my concern for you is genuine.
You could even say I pity you.
Pity... me?
Yes, I pity you from the bottom of my heart.
You have no idea how to be loved other
than to do what people expect of you,
yet you are forced to confront
a past that you never wanted.
Allow me to congratulate you,
with all of the pity and
compassion I can offer.
Well done overcoming the trial!
I was convinced that you
were incapable of it.
It's hard to thank you when
you congratulate me that way.
You said you didn't think I could do it.
Are you reconsidering that?
You're right. I know I've
worried you a great deal.
All I've been able to do is lose my nerve.
I've caused so much trouble for
Puck, for Subaru... for everyone.
But they all saved me.
I was utterly useless,
and they lent me a helping hand.
It made me realize that I can't
just go on being discouraged.
You say the same things Subaru-kun did.
Are you simply repeating his words?
Roswaal-sama!
Your borrowed words, the place
that has been prepared for you,
and even your attempts at the trial were
decisions made only after the stage was set.
Yet even knowing that, Subaru-kun
urges you to do terrible things.
That's not true! Subaru wants—
We both know him.
He was not speaking with logic or reason,
but only gave you an exceptionally
loud pep talk. Am I wrong?
He imposed his self-satisfaction on you,
forcing you to fit his ideal with the
emotional assertion that you could do it.
I understand. I truly do.
After all, he and I...
are two of a kind.
You and Subaru are two of a kind?
What does that mean?
That we both force our ideals
upon the women we love.
I'm sure he has spoiled you
and treated you with
utmost kindness and care.
He never even considered that you
are not a normal girl, did he?
The you he loves is the ideal you
that lives within his own mind.
Am I wrong?
Is that all?
That's the only thing that makes
you think you're like him?
If that's all you want to say...
You and Subaru aren't the same at all.
Subaru told me that I was a pain in the ass.
What?
He asked who I thought I was,
causing trouble for him when he's done so much.
He told me not to keep brooding
over what's in the past.
He said I was all talk,
and he couldn't put up with it.
And everything he said was right.
I was weak, all talk,
and insufficient in every way.
Subaru truly sees me for who I am.
So I know you and Subaru are nothing alike.
When I want to do something,
when I wish I could change,
he takes my hand and helps me.
He taught me that there are people
who would say that for me.
You do not think he was simply deceiving you?
All to tactfully get you back on your feet?
No. He wasn't lying.
What Subaru felt when he said he
believed in me won't turn into a lie.
I won't let it.
I'll turn the lies into wishes.
That's what I need to do right now,
and what I want to do.
You just continue to change.
This is exceedingly difficult
for me to accept.
Roswaal?
Your decision is priceless,
and your will to walk forward is noble.
This is precisely why I pity you.
The decision you've made that
justifies you getting hurt
is already meaningless in this
world that will soon end.
The world... will end?
More precisely, it is moving toward its end.
This world has strayed from the correct path
and now proceeds toward
the wrong destination.
The Sanctuary and the royal selection
have already lost all meaning.
Roswaal?
Why do you sound like you're giving up?
Weren't you... Weren't you and
I the ones who started this?
And you'd give up before it's over?
I won't allow that!
Then what is it you wish to do?
I don't know!
But what's wrong is wrong!
Don't give up!
That's just too selfish!
You really do sound just like Subaru-kun.
How much of your boastful speech
can ever be realized, I wonder?
That's what I'm about to show you.
In the graveyard... no,
outside the Sanctuary, too.
Emilia-sama...
I'm going now, Ram.
I promise I'll take care of
the favor you asked of me.
It was my teacher and I who started it.
That is the one thing you
got wrong, Emilia-sama.
It seems her resolve is far
stronger than I realized.
Roswaal-sama, how much of our
conversation did you hear?
I saw you kneel before her.
You are quite the actress.
I have heard that you
assisted them with Garfiel.
Of course, I know you believed
it was the right thing to do.
What do you intend to do now?
What I desire has not changed,
though I am now forced to
work a bit harder for it.
What shall I...
Remain here and await Emilia-sama's return.
If no one were here to
welcome her brave soul back,
even my own heart would ache for her.
The reason I took that bet was because it
seemed like my best chance at getting my wish.
Hello, Ram-san.
It's a lovely evening, isn't it?
The breeze feels so cool.
You're the boy who was with Barusu.
Natsuki-san just can't seem
to see you as an enemy.
If he's right,
I believe we can assist you in
getting what you really want.
So annoying.
Huh?
I said you're annoying.
Give me more details.
That's my idea.
What do you think?
If you want my help, I have three conditions.
First, I'm strongly in favor
of taking Garfiel down a notch.
But after you do that,
you must leave him to me.
Got it.
Then there's Emilia-sama.
Make Barusu do something about her.
I think that will be up to
Natsuki-san and Emilia-sama.
So... I feel as if the third
one is going to be a doozy.
Fool.
Just don't tell Barusu why I took this bet.
I don't want to give up my last endgame.
I suppose it would be easy to get
here if one used clairvoyance.
Did I not order you to wait for Emilia-sama?
Yes, you did.
Then tell me.
For what reason did you come here?
It's simple.
I've come to take you away...
from the witch's delusions.
Delusions, eh?
It has been some years since
you pointed your wand at me,
but it's a shame you did so here,
and that you called them "delusions."
I've always considered them such.
I just never said it out loud.
Is it not obvious?
Obvious...
Well, from your perspective, your humiliating
days spent yielding to me have been long.
I considered your behavior to be your
way of expressing your devotion.
Beating up Garf served two
purposes: to fulfill my goal,
and to attempt to rectify his idiocy.
I have no idea what they planned
to do if I hadn't been there.
I cannot deny that it all
worked out well in the end.
Subaru-kun will naturally choose to walk
a fine line in the final confrontation.
But the one thing Barusu has
going for him is his timing.
Betting on that one good quality
he has wasn't a mistake.
You have the book, yes?
In the place designated
for the final showdown,
at the stage when you take action yourself,
there's no way you don't have the Tome of
Wisdom that you rely on above all else.
I have never once forgotten
the one and only vow that
you and I exchanged.
Those who wield the sword
should die by the sword,
those who rely on magic should die by magic,
and those who give themselves
to fire should die by fire.
And those who ask favors of a
demon should die by that demon.
Whatever one relies upon should be the
thing that brings about their death.
And now the time has come.
Now that I have lost that which
I desired, I offer myself to you.
If you don't mind that
I am but an empty husk,
you may do as you please
with me. That was our vow.
Whether I let you live
or kill you is up to me.
You can finally achieve your retribution.
After all...
You had no choice but to swear
loyalty against your will
to one of the men who destroyed
your homeland, and live with him.
Although you had to do it after losing your
horn and your ability to maintain your form,
suffering of this degree is uncommonly rare.
There is no pawn more useful than you.
Which is why it is such a shame...
Your decision was just the slightest bit...
premature.
It is impressive that you created a situation in
which I had to carry the Tome of Wisdom.
You should have overlooked this last step
toward the action I was planning to take.
That alone is the true shame!
This is the precious young
girl who offered her own life
to save her friend by becoming
the Sanctuary's core.
But my objective does not involve her.
You intend to use this magic
crystal to cast great magic?
Great enough to change the weather.
In accordance with the Tome, I will
make snow fall in the Sanctuary.
In order to use that magic,
I require tremendous focus and
a highly delicate use of mana.
If I had been engaged in that,
you most definitely
could have shot me.
There would have been no meaning in that.
And there is meaning in forcing me into
capitulation when I am in my best condition?
Or did you simply want to destroy
me as quickly as possible?
No. You truly don't
understand anything at all.
I won't allow your wish to come true.
Being offered a husk of you after your
wish was realized would mean nothing.
Receiving you in a broken
state would not satisfy me.
Well, how very greedy of you.
But do you believe you can defeat me now?
No, I'm sure I can't.
My understanding of your power
is second only to your teacher's.
Then how, exactly, do you
intend to achieve your goal?
I cannot win alone.
That much is clear. So...
If it's two against one,
I guess we have the advantage?
So this is the main reason you
agreed to Subaru-kun's plan?!
I told you, Roswaal-sama.
I'm going to take you away
from the witch's delusions.
And I'm just a passing stray spirit.
Well, time to pick up
where we left off before!
Come!
As you wish!
I have to run... I have to run!
Rem-san?
But... But, but... That can't...
But... Rem-san is...
But... I know this is what Subaru would do!
So...
Rem-san...
My, what an adorable little girl.
You must be the smaller maid, then?
Are you shaking?
Don't worry.
I'm sure your bowels are
absolutely beautiful.
Good girl.
I'll send you to meet the angels.
Petra!
Frederica-neesama!
You are a bad girl, Petra!
I told you to run away.
You will be punished later!
Right... Right!
How lovely.
You must be the bigger maid, then.
I'm so glad you're both together,
and such good friends at that.
I'll lay out your bowels side by side
and find out if their insides
go well together, too.
From start to finish, not a word
you've just said makes any sense.
I cannot call it a tasteful way of thinking.
Demihuman blood, I see.
But after an experience in the royal capital
that nearly killed me, my skills have improved.
You can't handle me.
I do wish I could lay blame on the
person who failed to finish you then.
Petra, get outside the mansion now.
B-But... Nee-sama...
I do not know who sent you,
but Petra and I appear to be your targets.
Yes.
Two maids and a little spirit girl.
I've never cut open a spirit,
so I'm quite excited.
Go!
Right!
Your personality is worse than your taste.
She's a good girl.
I am most proud of her!
Nee-sama...
Maybe Beatrice-sama can do something!
In here!
No...
Here?! No...
Not here, either!
Not here...
She's not here, either.
Nee-sama is...
Rem-san is...
Subaru...
Help me!
All right. You got it, Petra.
Huh?
Sorry I'm late, but I'm here to help.
I'm glad you're okay, Petra.
It's you, Subaru? You came for us?
It's me, and I did.
Subaru, Frederica-neesama is—
Just leave it all to me!
...is what I'd like to say, but if I rush
in there, I'll be dead in a heartbeat.
So I sent some super-strong
reinforcements instead.
For a night of reunion,
the people in the way are
a little too in the way.
Why do you insist on aiming
just below my chest every time?
I suppose you could call it my hobby.
I am the Bowel Hunter, after all.
My hobby is cutting open bellies!
The boss likes to say...
that the best defense is a good offense.
So if I use a shield meant for
defense to attack instead...
The best defense and the
best offense come together,
making me the strongest one here, right?!
Don't ya think so, Big Sis?
Whoa, you're huge!
Wait, are you my sister?!
I feel like I should call
you "Big Bro" instead.
Don't be so rude the moment
we see each other again!
Garf, you have grown quite big.
That just sounds like sarcasm!
You're the one who's way too damn huge!
So...
Can I interrupt your happy reunion now?
How nice of ya to wait for us.
Yo, Sis—
Big Sis, do you know a chick named Rem?
Yes, she's in the mansion.
Subaru-sama said she was Ram's sister.
Get Rem outta here as soon
as you get an opening.
I'm gonna have my hands full with this bitch.
What are you saying?
Sorry, Big Sis.
She ain't the type I can take on
while worryin' about who's behind me.
Garf...
You see my arm, don't ya?
This is the shield you and I
played with when we were kids.
It was runnin' with you that
made me the strongest one there is.
Bring it on, bitch in black!
We'll celebrate me gettin'
out of the Sanctuary!
The first thing I'm gonna do is
bash up the first wall in my way!
Reunion of Roars
Why are you here? I never called for you.
Sorry, but I'm a guy who shows
up whether he's been called or not.
You are as self-serving as ever, I suppose.
That's right. I'm selfish.
I'm getting you out of here, Beatrice.
This time, you're gonna let me
drag you out into the sunlight,
and then we're gonna play until your
dress is black with mud!